少了我
這渺小的鎮
My little home
我渺小的家
This little town
不缺我一人
They don't need me
這簡單的笑
My simple life
我簡單的命
This simple grin
我已不信任
They betray me
你眼裡的謊
Their lying eyes
虛假的笑容
My cracking shell
心上的刀痕
Their phony smiles
臉上的淚痕
My low morale
感情間的砲火
我抵抗已盡了全力
The emotional warfare
has got the best of me
只要少了我
就不會有糾紛
When you're without me
it'll be easy to share
如果需要我
就假裝我在那兒
And if you need me
you can pretend I'm there
你看不到我
再也不用見到面
You'll never see me
we'll never meet again
就算少了我
你還有其他朋友
'Cause even without me,
you have your other friends
我總好奇
I wonder how
他們會怎麼想
they'd think of me
如果我就此離去
if I left them
他們哪會在乎
They wouldn't mind
他們哪會介意
they wouldn't care
我也沒給他們機會
I wouldn't let them
沒有歌謠
No serenade
沒有音樂
no lullaby
沒有故事
no metaphor
能讓我回頭
can change my mind
畢竟遙遠的那端
不過是我的「很久很久以前」
'Cause somewhere out there
is my "Once upon a time"
只要少了我
就不會有糾紛
When you're without me
it'll be easy to share
如果需要我
就假裝我在那兒
And if you need me
you can pretend I'm there
你看不到我
再也不用見到面
You'll never see me
we'll never meet again
就算少了我
你還有其他朋友
'Cause even without me,
you have your other friends
只要少了我...
When you're without me...
如果需要我...
And if you need me...
你看不到我...
You'll never see me...
就算少了我...
'Cause even without me...
沒有區別
大家都說月球是
每個太空人
They say that the moon
is a place that every astronaut
都夢想去的地方
dreams of going some day
我發覺我也沒有區別。
and I found myself no different.
我也發現孤單
可以治好
I had also figured that
being alone would be
我的忌妒心。
the answer to my jealousy.
真是完美。
It was perfect.
我終於找到了：
I had found it;
一個我可以獨處的地方，
又不會不知道要幹嘛。
the place where I could be alone,
but not truly lost.
一個我可以感到開心的地方，
即使遠離了朋友；
The place I could be happy
while away from my friends;
我可以呼吸自己的空氣，
不用跟別人分享。
where I could breathe my own air,
sharing it with none.
遨遊星雲
沒邀我的派對！
...哦... 他們怎麼可以！？
...oh... HOW COULD THEY!?
我，簡直，不敢，相信！
I. Can't. BELIEVE IT!!
他們開了派對沒邀我！
沒邀 Pinkie!
They had a party without me!
Without PINKIE!
唉，我——
誰會這樣做！
I mean, you--
you just don't DO that!!
哼！
Hmmm!
但管這麼多？
講得好像
他們得遵守一樣...
But who cares? It's not like
they need to
follow that rule NOW...
嗯，我，
Pinkamena Diane Pie,
定了這些規則。
I mean, I,
Pinkamena Diane Pie,
made the rule.
而如果我，
Pinkamena Diane Pie,
不在那邊，
And if I,
Pinkamena Diane Pie,
am not there at all,
那他們就
不用遵守規則。
then they won't HAVE
to follow the rule.
這是個雙贏。
他們在下面很好的話，
It's a double-win.
They're fine down THERE,
我在，這邊，也很好！
and I am fine. Right. HERE!
在這月球上
小馬鎮，我曾經愛著你
Ponyville, I was in love with you
但我想換換新模式
but I'm trying something new
反正不缺我一人
Ya don't need me now
我知道，聽來有點好過頭
I knew it was too good to be true
我知道我們都得輸
I knew that we'd both lose
而你也讓我失望
and you've let me down
是時候說再見
It's time to say goodbye
我學會了飛天
'cause I've learned how to fly
最近不是很想看到彼此
Don't wanna see you anytime soon
這裡沒有多少壓力
All tension's thin out here
覆蓋這冰冷的大氣
in this cool atmosphere
我看，我就活在這月球上
so, I'll be living here on the moon
La da da da da
La da da da da da
看看我，在這裡自己散步
Look at me, trottin' here on my own
看看我都飛了多遠
I mean, look how far I've flown
我已經習慣了這裡
It's already growing on me
現在想一想，
我們再也不會見面
Come to think of it,
you'll never see me again
連問好都不要問我
Don't even ask me how I've been
最好是不要想我
and don't even think about me
是時候說再見
It's time to say goodbye
我學會了飛天
'cause I've learned how to fly
最近不是很想看到彼此
Don't wanna see you anytime soon
這裡沒有多少壓力
All tension's thin out here
覆蓋這冰冷的大氣
in this cool atmosphere
我看，我就活在這月球上
so, I'll be living here on the moon
在這月球上
Here On The Moon
這不是什麼躲貓貓遊戲
This is no game of hide and seek
我估計是需要時間冷靜
I guess I just need time to think
所以，面對現實
So, face the facts
因為我不會回家
'Cause I won't be back
是時候說再見
It's time to say goodbye
我學會了飛天
'cause I've learned how to fly
最近不是很想看到彼此
Don't wanna see you anytime soon
這裡沒有多少壓力
All tension's thin out here
覆蓋這冰冷的大氣
in this cool atmosphere
我看，我就活在這月球上
so, I'll be living here on the moon
我不是在玩躲貓貓
I'm not playing hide and seek
只是需要自己思考
I just need time to think
所以我就在這月球上想一想
So I'll be thinking here on the moon
La da da da da
La da da da da da
星際渡假
自從我跑到這
一切都像在過節
Ever since I ran away
it's been just like a holiday
我有一次永久
渡假的機會
I got to go on
a getaway that never ends
上頭這有好多東西
There's lots up here to do and see,
感覺就像個大驚喜
it's like a big round mystery
只有我
不需要其他朋友
It's just me
and I don't need my friends
月球是多麼完美
專屬於我這粉色呆頭
The moon is a perfect place
for a silly pink pony like me
最棒的地方
獻給 Pinkie
The most amazing place
for Pinkie
要是你看得到我
你會知道我滿臉笑容
And if you saw my face
you'd know I'm filled with glee
只有我在月球上這麼開心
Nobody rocks the moon like me
我有我要的一切
感覺像給我開得派對
I have all I could ever need,
it's like a party just for me
往上看就能看到家園
If I look up I can see my home
從外面看感覺美多了
亮綠地和亮藍天
It looks much better from outside,
it's bright green land and bright blue sky
不曉得我幹嘛呆在那
I wonder why I stayed there for so long
月球是多麼完美
專屬於我這粉色呆頭
The moon is a perfect place
for a silly pink pony like me
最妙的地方
獻給 Pinkie
It's the most wonderful place
for Pinkie
要是你看得到我
你會知道我滿臉笑容
And if you saw my face
you'd know I'm filled with glee
只有我在月球上這麼開心
Nobody rocks the moon like me
只有我！
No, they don’t!
這裡有點兒冷，而且也有點黑
It's kinda cold up here and kinda dark too
看著那顆藍色彈珠
我也有點憂鬱
I see that bright blue marble
and it makes me kinda blue
這裡沒有多少空氣
地板也不怎綠
I don't get much atmosphere
and I don't get much grass
但就算在太空中，也聽的到我的笑
But even in space, you can hear me laugh
月球是多麼完美
專屬於我這粉色呆頭
The moon is a perfect place
for a silly pink pony like me
最夢幻的地方
獻給 Pinkie
The most fantastic place
for Pinkie
要是你看得到我
你會知道我滿臉笑容
And if you saw my face
you'd know I'm filled with glee
只有我在月球上這麼開心
Nobody rocks the moon like me
(只有我！)
(No, they don’t!)
只有我在月球上這麼開心
Nobody rocks the moon like me
只有我！
No, they don’t!
只有我在月球上這麼開心！
Nobody rocks the moon like me!
(只有我！)
(No, they don’t!)
終將打開
我這一生
從未錯得如此過。
I had never been
so wrong before in my life.
僅僅因為我不能
分享我呼吸的空氣
For the fact alone that
I couldn't share the air I breathed
我那張逐漸下垂的笑臉
就多了條煩惱的皺紋
brought an agonizing twitch
in my slowly sinking smile.
儘管這聽起來很荒唐
我哭了。
I would go as far as to say,
I started to cry.
我也只剩下哭了。
And that's just what I did.
轉瞬間，我明白了
把自己關在這裡
Right then, I realized
that trapping myself here
是個粗魯的決定，
was a rather rash decision,
而命運不會容忍我。
and would not be tolerated by fate.
我的朋友沒了，如此
我的笑容也是。
My friends were gone,
and therefore, so is my smile.
我向身旁的
星星訴苦
但它們不回應。
I expressed my sorrow to the stars
around me, but they
wouldn't respond.
它們甚至
不知道我的存在。
They didn't even
acknowledge my presence.
朋友會
但我已經沒有了。
Friends would,
but I didn't have those anymore.
我又哭了。
I cried again.
風暴席捲，在這牆內。
The storm is raging inside these walls.
心上打的詰，
終將打開。
The knots of emotion
will come undone.
終將打開。
Come undone.
現實
分隔的世界
Worlds so far apart
被遺忘的心
hearts hung out to dry
我仍想問好
They'll have my regards
只望有時間
just wish we had time
已經過太久
It's been much too long
自從上次見
since I've their eyes
放手的念頭
Trying to let go
我從未想過
was never on my mind
但誰能從，謊言中分出現實
But who can tell lies from reality
當每個人看法一致？
when everyone sees the same?
誰又能夠
寫下銀河的每一哩
And who can spell out
the miles of the galaxies
當它就是太多空間？
when there's just too much space?
而它就是太多空間
And there's just too much space
聽好你字句
Listen to your words
否則就成玩物
or they will pass you by
每個人聽見
Everyone who heard
都會看穿謊言
will see right through your lies
想像自己與星群
飄在太空中
It's not hard to imagine
yourself out in space
的確很簡單
floating with the stars
但當真的發生時，
But with everything that happens,
在那處境下
happening all around you
你也不再是你
It's just not who you are
但誰能從，謊言中分出現實
But who can tell lies from reality
當每個人看法一致？
when everyone sees the same?
誰又能夠
寫下銀河的每一哩
And who can spell out
the miles of the galaxies
當它就是太多空間？
when there's just too much space?
而它就是太多空間
And there's just too much space
你是否會屏棄
你所知一切？
Would you turn your back
on everything you know?
並且不往回看
並且不知道去向？
and not look back,
and not know where to go?
分隔的世界
Worlds so far apart
被遺忘的心
hearts hung out to dry
我仍想問好
They'll have my regards
他們一直在心上
they're always on my mind
但誰能從，謊言中分出現實
But who can tell lies from reality
當每個人看法一致？
when everyone sees the same?
誰又能夠
寫下銀河的每一哩
And who can spell out
the miles of the galaxies
當它就是太多空間？
when there's just too much space?
而它就是太多空間
And there's just too much space
還在月球
我不斷欺騙自己
I've been lying to me
試圖讓我相信
Tried to get me to see
我應該自由奔放
That I belong somewhere free
但是
But free
自由何意？
The meaning is gone
我只覺孤獨
I just feel alone
想留下來的念頭
My intentions to stay
很快就消逝不見
Have quickly faded away
不確定該說什麼
I don't quite know what to say
但，嘿
But hey
流淚也沒用
I know tears are loose
我沒有藉口
I have no excuse
看著那青
Watch as the blue
漸漸換膚
Changes its hue
我突然映出
I come into view
我沒有選項
I don't have to choose
因為想你，我同
'Cause I miss you, too
但我還在月球
But I'm still on the moon
我還在月球
I'm still on the moon
我好幾次想起來
Countless times I remember
一些亂湊的回憶
Memories made together
曾說過會待在那頭
Said I'd be there forever
那頭
ever
但現在
But now
眼下的雨
The rain in my eyes
正在這層
is floating in these
滿天星飄蕩
star-covered skies
看著那青
Watch as the blue
漸漸換膚
Changes its hue
我突然映出
I come into view
我沒有選項
I don't have to choose
因為想你，我同
'Cause I miss you, too
但我還在月球
But I'm still on the moon
我沒有選項
I don't have to choose
因為想你，我同
'Cause I miss you, too
但我還在月球
But I'm still on the moon
我還在月球
I'm still on the moon
還在月球
Still on the moon
來自
家的訊息
小馬鎮，致 Pinkie Pie...
Ponyville to Pinkie Pie...
你突然不見
我們都不知為何
Seems you've left us,
and we're all still wond'ring why
小馬鎮，致 Pinkie Pie...
Ponyville to Pinkie Pie...
我們還愛你
別躲起來
We still love you,
don't you hide
如你聽得見
你應該知道怎麼辦...
If this reaches you,
you'll know just what to do...
這裡是小馬鎮，致 Pinkie Pie
This is Ponyville to Pinkie Pie
只是想要跟你說
just wanted you to know
我們想你
我們只希望你回家
that we miss you,
and we wish that you were home
但我們也沒有權力
說你的去處
but it's not our place to
say where you should go
看來我一直對自己撒謊
Seems that I've been lying to myself
從未如此困難
it's never been so hard
我的蹄子好像
帶我走太過
and I think my hooves
have taken me too far
我想我該停下
聽聽我的想法
Guess it's time I stopped and
listened to my heart
但是，看來我們已陷入了僵局
But here are we sitting at an impasse
困在這月球
Trapped on the moon
火箭已飛走
我們已不在家鄉
Rocketship is gone
and I'm not where I belong
雖然我試著說服自己
Though I've tried convincing otherwise
我感到好孤獨
I'm feeling so alone
什麼事都看著好
陰沉灰暗
Things aren't looking on the
bright side anywhere
要是我有路回家——
If I just had some way home--
——我們帶你走
--we'll take you there
Pinkie Pie, 正是時刻
Pinkie Pie, the time has come
還來得及，你就上來
It's not too late, so just hop on
準備好沒，Pinkie Pie?
Are you ready, Pinkie Pie?
要不要跟，Pinkie Pie?
Are you with us, Pinkie Pie?
聽得見嗎, Pinkie Pie?
Can you hear us, Pinkie Pie?
聽得——
Can you--
現在，看來我們終於能夠回家
Here are we flying home together
跟月球說再見
Last glimpse of the moon
悲劇已趕走
我們已看見家鄉
Tragedy is gone,
this is where we all belong
我是誰？
Who am I?
我怎麼連
想都沒想過
How could I
not even think for a single second
我沒有你們的干涉
會多麼悲慘，
how dismal I would be
without your intervention,
不開心的事就不想
自己一個人笑？
prevent unpleasantness
and smile lacking your presence?
厭倦一直叫自己
思考世間難題
Flagging to present myself
with the hardest lesson of all
但我也不過是個跳梁小丑
but it's just a fool's errand
上演一齣影射自己極端的劇；
projecting a mask of its own rejection;
鬧劇，幌子，真是一齣幻想劇。
a farse, a lie of it's own invention.
一千里遠
我在準備放手，讓他們接手
I'm letting it go, and letting them in
正思考著要怎麼重起
pondering for a way to begin
乾乾淨淨，俐俐落落
coming out clean, cleaning up nice
我在準備改變
讓他們幫我
They're shaping me up
and taking me in
撫平傷痛並帶我向前
forgiving my pain and riding the wind
是否回家就會
改變一切
Will everything change
when we arrive?
星群墜落
前所未有的快
The stars are falling
faster than before
月亮招喚
但地球招更猛
The moon is calling,
but earth is calling more
喔哦，噢
Whoa, ohhh
現在是否看清？
now can't ya see?
喔哦，噢
Whoa, ohhh
自由真是清新
so good to be free
喔哦
Whoa
我不需要任何東西
I don't need anything
因為我就—
because I'm just,
—就已經是我自己
I'm just who I want to be
就是自己
I'm just me
在太空中，是真的孤獨
It's terribly lonely out in space
很少笑聲，笑容抹滅
laughter is rare, and smiles erased
朋友消失，噢
我是怎樣？
friendship is gone;
oh, what had I done?
但，我學到教訓
不會跑掉
But, now that I've learned,
I'll stay for a while
我已經飛了
一千里遠
now that I've burned
ten-hundred miles
我不會再來，不怎麼好玩
I'll never go back, it wasn't much fun
太陽落下
前所未有的快
The sun is setting
faster than before
生命招喚
就在我家門口
But life is stirring
just outside the door
喔哦，噢
Whoa, ohhh
現在是否看清？
now can't ya see?
喔哦，噢
Whoa, ohhh
自由真是清新
so good to be free
喔哦
Whoa
我不需要任何東西
I don't need anything
因為我就—
because I'm just,
—就已經是我自己
I'm just who I want to be
就是自己...
I'm just me...
喔哦...
Whoa...
噢...
Oooh...
喔哦，噢
Whoa, ohhh
現在是否看清？
now can't ya see?
喔哦，噢
Whoa, ohhh
自由真是清新
so good to be free
喔哦
Whoa
我不需要任何東西
I don't need anything
因為我就—
because I'm just,
—就已經是我自己
I'm just who I want to be
就是自己
I'm just me
湛藍天空
再給自己夢一天
Dream yourself another day
再給自己睡一眠
Sleep another night away
跟那孤獨月球道晚安
Bid the lonely moon goodnight
撒下永遠閃耀的星光
Under the ever-starry light
扯扯筋骨，安安心靈
Rest your bones, your weary mind
閉上沈重雙眼，今晚
Close your tired eyes tonight
我會為你射一顆流星
I'll cast a shooting star for you
想許什麼願都會成真
All your wishes will come true
要是你曉得...
看，我也待過那頭
If you knew...
you see, I've been there, too
噢，那月球...
不是你這小馬的所處
Oh, the moon...
is no place for filly like you
太陽會起床...
給你的世界帶來亮光
The sun will rise...
and bring your world to life
湛藍天空...
會來給你指引
Bluer skies...
will be your only guide
再給自己夢一天
Dream yourself another day
再給自己睡一眠
Sleep another night away
給我等等
結局才不是這樣！
Wait a minute,
that's not how it ended!
就在這
我沒有理由沮喪
I have no reason to frown
我不需要轉過身
I don't need to turn around
現在哭還有何用
What's the use in crying now
我不敢相信所見
I can't believe my eyes
我撒了一個瞞天大謊
I told myself the perfect lie
但我現在已不想死掉
But I don't feel like dying now
即使我給自己安排
最厄的運
And even though I turned the odds
against myself
我發現我又再次被
他人所救
Again I find that I've been saved
by someone else
所以今晚，我會改過重來
So tonight, I will make it right
我仍不懂為何
我會想要獨自吞淚
Still I don't know why
I thought I'd swallow all my tears
一直以來，我都想得太歪
All along, I was thinking wrong
我花太久搞清
我所需就在這
It took me far too long to see that
all I need's right here
我所需就在這
All I need's right here
有人說我瘋狂
Some say I lost my mind
至少我終於學會了
at least I found it given time
我再也不這樣脆弱
I won't go down so easily
對啦，我知道很明顯
Yeah, it's easy enough to admit
我本來就是不適合
it never was a perfect fit
那月球還是太小了
The moon is just too small for me
所以今晚，我會改過重來
So tonight, I will make it right
我仍不懂為何
我會想要獨自吞淚
Still I don't know why
I thought I'd swallow all my tears
一直以來，我都想得太歪
All along, I was thinking wrong
我花太久搞清
我所需就在這
It took me far too long to see that
all I need's right here
我所需就在這
All I need's right here
所以今晚，我會改過重來
So tonight, I will make it right
我仍不懂為何
我會想要獨自吞淚
Still I don't know why
I thought I'd swallow all my tears
所以今晚，我會改過重來
So tonight, I will make it right
我仍不懂為何
我會想要獨自吞淚
Still I don't know why
I thought I'd swallow all my tears
一直以來，我都想得太歪
All along, I was thinking wrong
我花太久搞清
我所需就在這
It took me far too long to see that
all I need's right here
我所需就在這
All I need's right here